

# FULL-STACK ENGINEER FRONT-END ENGINEER BACKEND ENGINEER REACT-NATIVE/ELECTRON ENGINEER

#### **ABOUT**

Experienced Full-Stack Developer with a track record of deploying and maintaining over 50 mobile, desktop, and web applications. Published author with over 30 articles and ten open-source projects, including two with over 50 GitHub stars. Released two npm packages with over 800 weekly downloads. Passionate about continuously learning and providing the best solutions for clients.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE



# Full-Stack Senior Software Engineer RAKBANK

RAKBANK is the trading name of the National Bank of Ras Al-Khaimah

# Feb 2023 to Present (2 Months)

- Lead the pioneering integration of artificial intelligence (AI) technologies within RAKBANK, including the implementation of semantic search, embedding techniques using ADA, and the utilization of advanced language models such as GPT-4, GPT Turbo 3.5 for intent classification, categorization, and other relevant applications.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to identify and understand business requirements, translating them into technical solutions that leverage AI capabilities.
- Architect and design scalable and efficient software systems, ensuring high performance, reliability, and security standards are met.
- Work on multiple projects simultaneously, showcasing versatility as a polyglot engineer proficient in various programming languages and frameworks such as Java, Node.js, Python, React, React Native, and Spring Boot.
- Develop and maintain full-stack applications, encompassing both front-end and back-end components, with a focus on delivering exceptional user experiences and seamless integration with existing systems.

- in linkedin.com/in/rajaosama
- rajaosama.me@gmail.com
- **(**\$\displaysquare +971-554066253

## CLICK HERE FOR MY PORTFOLIO

## **RELEVANT SKILLS**

- Angular Js
- React JS
- React Native
- Node Js
- GCP
- Electron
- Java
- Python
- Javascript
- Vue Js
- Firebase
- MongoDB
- SQL
- Docker
- C#
- SpringBoot
- Kafka
- Next Js

# CLICK HERE TO SEE THE BLOGS I WRITE

- in linkedin.com/in/rajaosama
- rajaosama.me@gmail.com
- **(**971-554066253



## **Full-Stack Senior Software Engineer**

#### **Albatha Next**

Albatha Next is creating new digital businesses and supporting the digital transformation of the Albatha Group.

April 2022 to Feb 2023

(A Year)

As a Full-Stack Senior Software Engineer at Albatha Next, I have been responsible for designing, developing, and optimizing the front-end application scaffolding on Next JS using a future-proof project structure and pre-commit setups such as Husky, EsLint, Jest, and TS Checks to ensure code quality. I have also developed and deployed applications built on React JS, Next JS, and SpringBoot.

In collaboration with the Medical and Automotive teams, I have worked to build the best and most reliable applications for these market segments, focusing on all of the company's main product lines. I have been involved in the entire software development lifecycle, from gathering requirements to release.

I have also worked to bring about change in the business by introducing the use of modern development tools such as Next JS and Tailwind CLI. Through my work, I have added SpringBoot and event-driven architecture and microservices to my skill set, enabling me to build scalable applications.



#### Sr. Full Stack Engineer

#### **ATOMPOINT**

A consultancy company that works with enterprises, organizations, and businesses from various industries, helping them create and launch products that are used by thousands of customers around the world

March 2020 to April 2022 (2 years)

As a Sr. Full Stack Engineer at ATOMPOINT, a consultancy company that helps businesses create and launch products, I have developed, tested, and deployed 15+ applications and websites on various frameworks. I have also demonstrated strong ability in architecting infrastructures, backends, and frontends for performant and streamlined development, as demonstrated by creating an Uber-like water delivery mobile app based on GCP, NodeJS, and React Native.

In addition to my technical skills, I have also collaborated effectively on all stages of the software development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases. I have developed a webinar platform from scratch, including ideation, design, and development, and have experience in converting static sites to dynamic web applications using 11ty, contentful, and nodeJS. Overall, I am a highly skilled and experienced full stack engineer with a track record of delivering successful projects.



# Full-Stack Senior Software Engineer Dawood Fiber Mills LTD

A Formal Mills LTD - now a parent company that owns much business in Karachi and Dubai, including superstores

2017 to 2020 (3 years)

As a Full-Stack Senior Software Engineer at Dawood Fiber Mills, a parent company that owns multiple businesses in Karachi and Dubai, including superstores, I served as a technical lead with a successful track record in managing and resolving software-related issues. I demonstrated strong ability in developing 10+ in-house applications on various frameworks, and was skilled in creating mobile applications for Android and iOS, storefronts, and desktop applications, as well as integrating them with existing systems. I also provided extended support for the company's existing systems, including those of its sub-company, Dominion Stores.



Website Developer (Part Timer)

**NP Digitals LTD** 

A service provider call centre @karachi, Pakistan, dealing with clients in US 2016 to 2017 (2 years)

As a part-time Website Developer at NP Digitals, a service provider call center in Karachi, Pakistan, I gained experience in designing and developing websites and landing pages. I was skilled in optimizing application load times to ensure quick website performance, and was proficient in using PHP, HTML, CSS, and WordPress.

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**



Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Technology

Middlesex University, @Dubai

2022



Advanced Diploma In Software Engineering

APTECH, @Dubai

2017 - 2020



**Intermediate Degree in Pre Engineering** 

CMS College, @Karachi

2017 - 2019

#### MAJOR PROJECTS

#### Super Simple browser (Electron)

Super Simple Browser is an electron and react-based website browser with basic browsing functionality like tabs and navigation—a Gift for the open-source community. Link is attached to the title.

#### MP3 Remix(Electron)

mp3 remix was one of the applications on electron and reacted that I worked on. The concept of the application was to download music to the desktop, synced it with their website and whenever some one add a music to the bucket, it will auto-download from the desktop application.

#### **React-native foreground Service (React Native)**

RN-foreground-service is a tool for creating un-killable headless tasks for react native. It is the most comprehensive foreground service for react native on the market, featuring multi-tasks running from a single headless task, notification control such as buttons and on-notification click handling, and the ability to update notifications on the go. It was developed while creating an Uber-like water delivery app, WaterLink, and was designed to keep the app alive even when it is killed.

## WooShop (React Native)

Created an open-source e-commerce project built with React-native, Graph-QL, and woo-commerce. It was developed as a showcase application to demonstrate my React-native skills and uses woo-commerce by WordPress as the data source, connected to the app through Graph-QL. It supports authentication with JWT, browsing by filter, order creation, product listing, category listing, and cart, and has over 100 stars on GitHub.

I HAVE BUILT MANY MORE APPLICATIONS AND PROJECTS, BUT THE LIST IS TOO LONG TO INCLUDE HERE.